Guide to the Donald Gordon Papers, 1900-1988 UA.90.F46
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Donald Gordon Papers
1900-1988
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Gordon, Donald E.
UA.90.F46
31.25 Linear Feet (25 boxes)
Dr. Donald Gordon was an art historian and faculty member at the University of Pittsburgh from 1969 until his death in 1984. This collection contains research conducted by Dr. Gordon throughout the world pertaining to the Expressionist Movement, particularly the paintings of Ernst Kirchner, and early twentieth century Modern Art.
Biography
Donald Gordon was born in New York City in 1931. He attended Havard University for his bachellor's, master's, and doctoral degrees, the latter of which he earned in 1960. In the same year, he was hired as an associate professor of fine arts at Dickinson College. In 1969, Dr. Gordon came to the University of Pittsburgh as a professor of fine arts. He served as the chair of Pitt's Fine Arts department from 1969 to 1973.
Dr. Gordon was the author of three books: Ernst Ludwig Kirchner (1968), Modern Art Exhibitions 1900-1916: Selected Catalogue Documentation (1974), and Expressionism: Art and Idea (1984). He received several professionial awards and fellowships, including honors from the American Council of Learned Societies (1973-1974) and The Alexander Humboldt Foundation Fellowship from the Central Institute for Art History in Munich (1967-1968). In addition, he served on the Board of Directors for the Society for the Arts, Religion, and Contemporary Culture from 1974 until his death in 1984. He died of cancer at the age of 52 on April 10, 1984, at Montefiore Hospital in Pittsburgh.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Fine Arts Department in 1997.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains research and drafts of several of Dr. Donald Gordon's books and articles. This includes photographs and copies of many Expressionist paintings that are held in private or museum collections, as well as catalogs from Modern Art exhibitions from all over the world. Of particular note are Dr. Gordon's provenance files for all identifiable paintings by Ernst Kirchner. Also included are files pertaining to the various courses taught by Dr. Gordon at the University of Pittsburgh and his professional correspondence.
University of Pittsburgh; Faculty papers; Art, Modern -- 20th century -- History; Art and history; Art, Modern -- 20th century; Expressionism (Art); Kirchner, Ernst Ludwig; Gordon, Donald E.
- Ernst Ludwig Kirchner, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  In 1968 Dr. Gordon published a catalogue raisonné of the paintings of German Expressionist artist Ernst Ludwig Kirchner. This series includes files of provenance research for most of Kirchner's paintings, as well as correspondence with art museums and dealers throughout the United States and Europe pertaining to various Kirchner works. Additionally, there are photocopies of Kirchner's diaries and correspondence which were used by Dr. Gordon while researching the book.
  - Inventory of Kirchner Works, 1.
    This subseries contains the provenance files created by Dr. Gordon while reseachering the paintings of Ernst Kirchner. The majority of the files include a form created by Dr. Gordon which he or a correspondent would complete about an individual painting, listing the work's current and previous owners and exhibits, among other information. Some files also contain a photograph of the painting and correspondence.
    - Male Portrait in Profile (Männerkopf im Profil), 1, 1902-1903 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Valley Near Lichtenwalde (Die Mulde bei Lichtenwalde), 2, 1903/1920 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Seated Nude Seen from the Back (Sitzender weiblicher Akt von hinten), 3, 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Woman Embroidering (Stickende Frau), 4, 190-1905/1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Female Nude with Foliage Shadows (Macktes Mädchen mit Zweigschtten), 5, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Erich Heckel and Model in Studio (Erich Heckel und Modell im Atelier), 6, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Moonrise; Soldier and Girl (Mondaufgang; Soldat und Mädchen), 7, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Girl Asleep (Schlaffendes Mädchen), 8, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Girl on Sofa (Mädchen auf dem Sofa), 9, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Doris Standing (Doris stehend), 10, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Woman in Front of a Base of Sunflowers (Frauenkopf vor Sonnenblumen), 11, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bed of Flowers (Blumenbeete), 12, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Lake in Dresden Park (Parksee, Dresden), 13, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Priessnitz Bridge (Priessnitzbrücke), 14, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - The Loam Pit (Die Lehmgrube), 15, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Doris with Ruffed Collar (Doris mit Halskrause), 16, 1906/1908-1909 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Forest Scene (Waldstück), 17, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Child's Head (Kinderköpfchen), 18, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Trees in Autumn (Bäume im Herbst), 19, 1906/1908 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Girl on a Divan (Mädchen auf dem Diwan), 20, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin (Onkel Toms Hütte), 21, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Woman Near a Birch Grove (Frau von Birken), 22, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Grazing Horses (Pferde auf der Weide), 23, 1907/1926 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Self-porttrait with Pipe (Selbstbildnis mit Pfeife), 24, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Landcape, Road with Trees (Landschaft, Weg mit Bäumen), 25, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - The Green House (Grünes Haus), 26, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Fruit Trees (Obstbäume), 27, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Portrait of the Painter Heckel (Porträt des Malers Heckel), 28, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Trees in the Wind (Bäume im Wind), 29, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Girl in Forest (Mädchen im Wald), 30, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Nude reading (Rückenakt, lesend), 31, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Reclining Girl, (Liegendes Madchen), 32, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Portrait of a Man; Hans Frisch (Herrenbildnis; Hans Frisch), 33, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Emmy Frisch in the Rocking Chair (Emmy Frisch im Schaukelstuhl), 34, 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Emmy Frisch with Red Flowers (Emmy Frisch mit roten Blumen), 35, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Ferry to Übigau (Überfahrt Übigau), 36, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Fehmarn Houses (Fehmarn-Häuser), 37, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Old House, Fehmarn (Altes Haus auf Fehmarn), 38, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Portrait of a Woman in White (Frauenbildnis in weißem Kleid), 39, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Fehmarn Coast (Küste Fehmarn), 40, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - A Pond at Fehmarn (Fehmarnteich), 41, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Fehmarn Cabins (Fehmarn -Hütte), 42, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Two Seated Nudes (Zwei Sitzende Akte), 43, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Three Nudes in the Forest (Drei Akte im Walde), 44, 1908/1920 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Nude Before Green Sofa (Macktes Mädchen vor grünem Sofa), 45, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - The Living Room; Interior with Two Women (Wohnzimmer; Inerieur mit zwei Mädchen), 46, 1908/1926 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Coffee Table (Kaffeetafel), 47, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - On Fehmarn Island (Auf Fehmarn), 47v, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Dodo and her Brother (Dodo und ihr Bruder), 48, 1908/1920 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Czardas Dancers (Czardastänzerinnen), 49, 1908/1920 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Nude in Bathtub, Seen from Above (Akt in Badewanne, von oben gesehen), 50, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Standing and Reclining Nude (Stehender und liegender Akt), 51, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Two Prostitutes (Zwei Dirnen), 52, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Street (Straße), 53, 1908/1919 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - White Horses in Circus Drill (Schimmeldressurakt), 54, 1908-1909/1933 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Reclining Nude (Liegender Akt), 55, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Reclining Nude with Pipe (Liegender Akt mit Pfeife), 56, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Girl Under Japanese Umbrella (Mädchen unter Japanschirm), 57, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Reclining Nude with Fan (Liegender Akt mit Fächer), 58, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Trees in Bloom I (Blühende Bäume I), 59, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Trees in Bloom II (Blühende Bäume II), 61, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Landscape in Spring (Frühlingslandschaft), 62, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Trees in Bloom III (Blühende Bäume III), 63, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Trees in Bloom IV (Blühende Bäume IV), 64, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Cherry Trees (Kirschbäume), 65, 1909/1920 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Trees with White Blossoms in Landscape (Landschaft mit weißblühenden Bäumen), and Acrobatic Dancer (Akrobatische Tänzerin) 66, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - House with Trees in Bloom (Haus mit blühenden Bäumen), 67, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Stübelallee in Dresden (Stübelalee in Dresden), 68, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Japanese Theater (Japanisches Theater), 69, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Wrestlers in a Circus (Ringkämpfer im Zirkus), 70, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Tavern (Weinstube), 71, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Red Tulips (Rote Tulips), 72, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Sunflowers (Sonnenblumen), 73, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Negro Dancer (Negertänzerin), 74, 1909/1920 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Russian Dancers (Russisches Tanzpaar), 75, 1909/1926 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Two Women with Masks (Zwei Mädchen mit Masken), 76, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Balancing Act (Beinequilibristen), 77, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Two Reclining Nudes (Zwei liegende Akte), 78, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Two Nudes on a Carpet (Zwei Akte auf Teppichen), 79, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Woman with Black Stockings (Frau mit schwarzn Strümpfen), 80, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Nude in Blooming Meadow (Mädchenakt auf blühender Weise), 81, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Woman before a Mirror (Dame vor dem Spiegel), 82, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Seated Girl with Hat (Sitzendes Mädchen mit Hut), 83, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Artists Going Off-Stage (Abtrende Artisten), 84, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Turks (Türke), 85, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Girls Bathing, Lake Moritzburg (Im See badende Mädchen, Moritzburg), 86, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Reclining Blue Nude with Straw Hat (Liegender blauer Akt mit Strohhut), 87, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Two Nude Women in the Forest (Zwei nckte Frauen im Wald), 88, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Two Pink Nudes at the Lake (Zwei rosa Ackte am See), 89, 1909/1920 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Three Nudes in Yellow, Green, and Orange (Drei Akte in Gelb, Grün und Orange), 90, 1909/1920 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Reclining Nudes in a Meadow (Badende in der Weise), 91, 1909/1926 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Two Green Nudes with Red Hair (Zwei grüne Mädchenakte mit rotem Haar), 92, 1909/1926 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Bathers in Moritzburg (Badende in Moritzburg), 93, 1909/1926 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Group of Bathers in Moritzburg (Madende Menschengruppe in Moritzburg), 94, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Four Bathers (Vier Badende), 95, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Nude Girls Talking (Nackte Mädchen unterhalten sich), 96, 1909/1926 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Three Nudes at the Moritzburg Lake (Drei Akte am See Moritzburg), 97, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Bathhouse Near Dresden (Badeanstahlt bei Dresden)/ Mountain Brook with Bridge (Waldbach mit Brücke), 98, 1909/ 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Streetcar in Dresden (Straßenbahn in Dresden), 99, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Flower Beds in the Dresden Gardens (Blumenbeete in Dresdener Park)/ Seated Nude in Blue and Orange (Sitzender Mädchenakt in Blau und Orange), 100, 1909/1920 / 1909-1910 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Broadleafed Plants, Botanical Garden (Botanischer Garten, Blattpflanzen), 101, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Group of Houses (Häusergruppe), 102, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Red Hause (Rotes Haus), 103, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - The Blue House in the Potholder District, Dresden (Das blaue Haus im Topflappenviertel, Dresden), 104, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Fränzi at Breakfast (Fränzi beim Frühstück), 105, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Seated Girl with Umbrella (Mädchen unter Sonnenschirm), 106, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Seated Girl (Sitzendes Mädchen), 107, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Bathing Nude in a Room (Badende im Raum), 108, 1090/1920 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Girl in a White Blouse Sunning Herself (Sich Sonnende in weißem Hemd), 109, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 109)
    - Bicycle Race Track (Radrennbahn), 110, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 110)
    - Lemons and Pears (Zitronen und Birnen), 111, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 111)
    - Still Life with Oranges and Tulips (Stilleben mit Orangen und Tulpen), 112, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 112)
    - Marcella, 113, 1909-1910 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    - Tightrope Dancers (Drahtseiltanz), 114, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 114)
    - Varieté; English Dancers (Varieté; Engllisches Tanzpaar), 115, 1910/1926 (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - Varieté Dancer (Varietétanzerin), 116, 19010/1920 (Box 1, Folder 116)
    - Bridge at the Priessnitz Estuary (Brücke an der Priessnitzmündung), 117, 1910/1920 (Box 1, Folder 117)
    - Tightrope Dancer M. (Drahtseiltänzerin M.), 118, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 118)
    - Riverboats on the Elbe near Dresedn (Boote auf der Elbe bei Dresden), 119, 1910/1920 (Box 1, Folder 119)
    - Self Portrait with Model, small version (Selbstbildnis mit Modell, Kleinformat), 120, 1910/1920 (Box 1, Folder 120)
    - Self Portrait with Model (Selbstverbildnis mit Modell), 121, 1910/1926 (Box 1, Folder 121)
    - Fränzi in Carved Chair (Fränzi vor geschnitztem Stuhl), 122, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 122)
    - Seated Girl; Fränzi (Sitzendes Mädchen; Fränzi), 123, 1910/1920 (Box 1, Folder 123)
    - Girl with Cat; Fränzi (Mädchen mit Katze; Fränzi), 124, 1910/1920 (Box 1, Folder 124)
    - Artist; Marcella (Artistin; Marcella), 125, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 125)
    - The Wooden Bowl (Die Holzschale), 126, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 126)
    - Landcscape with House (Landschaft mit Haus), 127, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 127)
    - Red Houses; Red January II (Rote Häuser; Roter Januar II), 128, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 128)
    - Houses with Flags (Beflaggte Häuser), 129, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 129)
    - Seated Nude on Orange Drape (Sitzender Akt auf orangem Tuch), 129v, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 130)
    - Dresden- Friedrichstadt (Dresden-Friedrichstadt), 130, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 131)
    - Windmill (Windmühle), 131, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 132)
    - Two Women in White in the Forest (Zwei weiße Damen im Walde), 132v, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 133)
    - House in Moritzburg; the White House (Moritzburger Haus; Das weiße Haus), 133, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 134)
    - Greenhouses (Gärtnereien), 134, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 135)
    - Flower Nurseries (Gärtnereien), 135, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 136)
    - Forest Road (Waldstraße), 136, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 137)
    - Sailboats (Segelboote), 137, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 138)
    - Müggelsee near Berlin with Blooming Chesnut Trees (Müggelsee bei Berlin mit blühenden Kastanienbäumen), 138, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 139)
    - Blue Girl in the Sun (Das blaue Mädchen in der Sonne), 139, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 140)
    - Two Girls under Umbrella (Zwei Mädchen unter Sonnenschirm), 140, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 141)
    - Nudes Playing Under the Tree (Spielende nackte Menschen unter Baum), 141, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 142)
    - In the Forest (Im Wald), 142, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 143)
    - The Deciduous Forest (Laubwald), 143, 1910/1920 (Box 1, Folder 144)
    - Nudes in the Sun, Moritzburg (Akte in der Sonne, Moritzburg), 144, 1910/1920 (Box 1, Folder 145)
    - Naked Couple in the Sun (Nacktes Paar in der Sonne), 145, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 146)
    - Three Bathers in Moritzburg (Drei Badende in Moritzburg), 146, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 147)
    - Boy and Girl (Bube und Mädchen), 147, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 148)
    - Nude Woman with Child, Study (Nackte Frau mit Kind, Studie), 148, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 149)
    - Nudes in Studio with Dutch Oven (Akte im Atelier mit Kachelofen), 149, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 150)
    - Profile of Fränzi Nude (Nackte Fränzi im Profil), 150, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 151)
    - Nude with Flowers (Akt mit Blumen), 151, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 152)
    - Two Nudes Seated Among Flowers (Zwei Sitzende Akte in Blumen), 152, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 153)
    - Girl with Cherries (Mädchen mit Kirschen), 153, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 154)
    - Nude Behind a Curtain; Fränzi (Nacktes Mädchen hinter Vorhang; Fränzi), 154, 1910/1926 (Box 1, Folder 155)
    - Two Nudes on Blue Couch (Zwei Akte auf blauen Sofa), 155, 1910/1920 (Box 1, Folder 156)
    - Nude with Painted Face (Akt mit geschminkten Gesicht), 156, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 157)
    - Seated Nude with Raised Arms (Sitzender Akt mit erhobenen Armen), 157, 1910/1926 (Box 1, Folder 158)
    - Dodo with a Large Fan (Dodo mit großem Fächer), 158, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 159)
    - Three Standing Nudes (Drei weibliche Akte),159, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 160)
    - Nude with Raised Arms (Halbakt mit erhobenen Armen), 160, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 161)
    - Panama Girls (Panamatänzerinnen), 161, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 162)
    - Nude Asleep (Schlafender weiblicher Akt), 162, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 163)
    - Standing Nude with Hat (Stehender Akt mit Hut), 163, 1910/1920 (Box 1, Folder 164)
    - Variety Show (Varietéparade), 164, 1910/1926 (Box 1, Folder 165)
    - Bareback Rider on a White Horse (Jockeyreiterin auf Schimmel), 165, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 166)
    - Still Life with Sculpture and Fruit (Stillebe mit Plastik und Früchten), 166, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 167)
    - Portrait of Erich Heckel (Bildnis Erich Heckel)l, 167, 1910/1920 (Box 1, Folder 168)
    - Bridge by the City Gate, Chemnitz (Pfortensteg Chemnitz), 168, 1910/1913 (Box 1, Folder 169)
    - Roofs and Buildings (Dächer und Gebäude), 169, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 170)
    - Railroad Bridge (Eisenbahnbrücke), 170, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 171)
    - Railroad Undrpass in Dresden-Löbtau (Eisenbahnüberführung Dresden-Löbau), 171, 1910/1926 (Box 1, Folder 172)
    - Ballet Lesson (Ballettraining), 172, 1910-1911 (Box 1, Folder 173)
    - Studio with Girls (Atelier mit Mädchen), 173, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 174)
    - Fränzi, 174, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 175)
    - Two Nudes with Bathtub and Oven (Zwei Akte mit Badetub und Ofen), 175, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 176)
    - Woman with Hands Together (Frau mit zusammengelegten Händen), 176, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 177)
    - Two Girls with Bathtub (Zwei Mädchen mit Badewanne), 177, 1909-1911/1920 (Box 1, Folder 178)
    - Fränzi with Bow and Arrow (Fränzi mit Pfeilbogen), 178, 1909-1911 (Box 1, Folder 179)
    - Fränzi on a Cushion (Fränzi auf Kissen), 179, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 180)
    - Half-Length Nude with Hat (Weiblicher Halbakt mit Hut), 180, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 181)
    - Dodo with Feather Hat (Dodo mit großem Federhut), 181/ Death of Archimedes (Der Tod der Archimedes), 181v, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 182)
    - Dodo Nude against Blue Background (Dodo Akt vor blauem Grund), 182, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 183)
    - Fränzi, Shoulder-Length Portrait (Fränzikopf), 183, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 184)
    - Nude Reclining on Drapery (Auf Tuch Liegender Akt), 184, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 185)
    - Portrait of a Woman (Frauenbildnis), 185, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 186)
    - Negro Dancer (Negertänzerin), 186, 1910-1911 (Box 1, Folder 187)
    - Negro Couple (Negerpaar), 187, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 188)
    - Couple Seated at the Table (Am Tisch sitzendes Paar), 188, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 189)
    - Two Women; Two Midinettes (Zwei Mädchen; Zwei Midinetten), 189, 1911/1922 (Box 1, Folder 190)
    - Conversation; Reclining Woman (Unerhaltung; Liegende Frau), 190, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 191)
    - Portrait of a Woman (Mädchenbildnis), 191, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 192)
    - Two Dancing Girls (Zwei Tänzerinnen), 192, 1910-1911 (Box 1, Folder 193)
    - Six Dancing Girls (Sechs Tänzerrinen), 193, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 194)
    - Five Bathers at the Lake (Fünf Badende am See), 194, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 195)
    - Two Nudes with Sculpture (Zwei Akte mit Skulptur), 195, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 196)
    - Step Dance (Steptanz), 196, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 197)
    - Otto and Maschka Mueller in the Studio (Otto und Maschka Mueller im Atelier), 197, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 198)
    - The Bosquet; Square in Dresden (Das Baskett; Platz in Dresden), 198, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 199)
    - Lake in Bohemian Forest (Böhmerwaldsee), 199, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 200)
    - Bohemian Circus (Böhmischer Zirkus), 200, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 201)
    - Landscape with Foreground Tree (Landschaft mit Baum im Vordergrund), 201, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 202)
    - Farm (Gehöft), 202, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 203)
    - Two Figures by the Lake (Zwei Figuren am See), 203, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 204)
    - Three Nudes in Front of Trees (Drei Akte vor Bäumen), 204, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 205)
    - Nudes under Trees (Akt unter Bäumen), 205, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 206)
    - Bather (Badende), 206, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 207)
    - Train-Station Aprroach: Löbtau Train Station (Bahnhofseinfahrt; Bahnhof Löbtau), 207, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 208)
    - Villa in the Park (Villa im Park), 208, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 209)
    - Villa near Grünau (Villa bei Grünau), 209, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 210)
    - City Tower (Der Stadturm), 210, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 211)
    - Garden Restaurant in Steglitz (Wirtsgarten in Steglitz), 211, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 212)
    - Interior with Couple (Interieur mit Paar), 212, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 213)
    - Two Nudes by the Window (Zwei Akte am Fenster), 213, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 214)
    - Girl with Blue Hat (Junges Mädchen mit blauem Hut), 214, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 215)
    - Portrait of Poet Guthmann (Bildnis Guthmann), 215, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 216)
    - Still Life in Yellow (Gelbes Stilleben), 216, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 217)
    - Still Life with Calla Lily (Stilleben mit Kalla), 217, 1911/1920 (Box 1, Folder 218)
    - Still Life with Mask (Stilleben mit Maske)/ Four Bathers (Vier Badende), 218, 1911/1913 (Box 1, Folder 219)
    - The Masked Ball (Maskenball), 219, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 220)
    - Negro Dancers (Negertanz), 220, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 221)
    - Unicycle Rider (Einradfahrer), 221, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 222)
    - The Russian Dancer Mela (Russische Tänzerin Mela), 222, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 223)
    - Girls Relaxing (Lungernde Mädchen), 223, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 224)
    - Two Nudes in Vertical Format (Zwei webiliche Akte in Hochformat), 224, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 225)
    - Nude with Mirror and Man (Rückenakt mit Spiegel und Mann), 225, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Nude with Two Mirrored Figures (Akt mit zwei Figuren im Spiegel), 226, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Pantomime Reimann: The Dancer's Revenge (Pantomime Reimann: Die Rache der Tänzerin), 227, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - The Russian Girl (Die Russin), 228, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Still Life with Covered Vase (Stilleben mit Gefäß), 229, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Still Life with Sculptures and Flowers (Stilleben mit Plastiken und Blumen), 230, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Still Life with Two Vases of Flowers (Stilleben mit zwei Blumenvasen), 231, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Still Life with Jug and African Bowl (Stilleben mit Krug und afrikanischer Schale), 232, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Teapot, Bottle, and Red Flowers (Teekanne, Flasche und rote Blumen), 233, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Still Life with Tulips, Wood-Carvings, and Hands (Stilleben mit Tulpen, Exoten und Händen), 234, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Girl in White Chemise (Mädchen in weißem Hemd), 235, 1912/1920 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Woman in Green Garden Cafe (Grüne Dame im Gartencafe), 236, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Woman with Dog I (Frau mit Hund I), 237, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Woman with Dog II (Frau mit Hund II), 238, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 14)